Aiyeniko Tomi Peter

Software Engineer / Frontend Engineer

tomiaiyeniko@gmail.com

GitHub: github.com/Tomi-pter, LinkedIn: Tomi Aiyeniko - LinkedIn, Portfolio: tomipter.com

A front-end developer and web accessibility advocate with 4+ years of experience that is highly adept at working both independently and collaborating in a team to build accessible and responsive web interfaces.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Frontend Engineer

Outliant, US (Remote)

January 2023 - present

- Developed and implemented user-friendly and visually appealing interfaces, translating design mockups and wireframes into UI using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Webflow, React, Next.js, AWS, Firebase.
- Ensured cross-browser and cross-device compatibility
- Collaborated with designers and backend developers to deliver fully immersive and functional websites and web apps
- Successfully deployed 2 projects (web apps) so far, resulting in a 200% increase in sales and interactions combined over the last 2 months.

Frontend Engineer

FStackDev, Abuja (Remote)

April 2021 - December, 2022

- Assisted in building and maintaining scalable, fully responsive and accessible websites/webapps for 20+ businesses and clients.
- Worked hand-in-hand with the back-end engineering team and design team in structuring and building websites/webapps to satisfy the needs of the client.
- Wrote automated tests using Jest, React testing library and Cypress ensuring 100% bug free shipping and deployment of production code.
- Collaborated with the backend team to integrate internal APIs and internal tooling applications.

Frontend Engineer (Contract)

August 2022 - October 2022

DellMarvis Smart Technologies Ltd. (Remote)

• I orchestrated, developed and launched the frontend infrastructure, design and functionality for DellMarvis' website using Nextjs, GSAP, Styled-Components, React-Leaflet and Formik.

Software Engineer

January 2020 - March 2021

NCPC (Nigerian Christian Pilgrims Commission), Abuja

- Developed a portal for pilgrimage application and interview scheduler that optimized pilgrimage applications and interview steps by over 50%.
- Implemented front-end technical solutions to meet project requirements.

Frontend Developer

July 2019 - December 2019

Zkyte Technologies, Abuja

- Collaborated with the design team to take client wireframes from conception to implementation.
- Worked in an Agile, collaborative space to receive design requirements, and test applications.
- Conducted research and assisted with new business scoping efforts, resulting in the acquisition of 7 new clients

Frontend Engineer (Intern)

March 2019 - July 2019

FStackDev

- Assisted in migrating legacy code to modern day standards.
- Assisted in removing bootstrap from company stack and moving to modern day css, thereby eliminating dead code and reducing bundle size by 20%.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Stack and Libraries: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, React.js, Next.js, Styled-Components, TailwindCSS, Redux/Redux Toolkit, Git/GitHub, REST APIs, GraphQL, GSAP, Framer-motion, SCSS/SASS, Bootstrap, jQuery, Leaflet.js, Chart.js, Webpack, Jest, React-Testing-Library, Cypress, Webflow, AWS, Firebase.

Skills: Communication, accessibility optimization, Search engine optimization, Googling, Test Automation, Agile. **Languages**: English.

EDUCATION

Landmark University 2016-2020 Bachelor of Science (B.Sc), Computer Science